The most lethal sniper in U.S. history.
American Sniper is a war, action film directed by Clint Eastwood.
Navy SEAL Chris Kyle takes his sole mission—protect his comrades—to heart and
becomes one of the most lethal snipers in American history.
His pinpoint accuracy not only saves countless lives but
also makes him a prime target of insurgents.
Despite grave danger and his struggle to be a good husband and father to his
family back in the States, Kyle serves four tours of duty in Iraq.
However, when he finally returns home, he finds
that he cannot leave the war behind.
Chris Kyle, played by Bradley Cooper.
Taya Renae Kyle, played by Sienna Miller.
Goat-Winston, played by Kyle Gallner.
Young Chris Kyle, played by Cole Konis.
Wayne Kyle, played by Ben Reed.
Debbie Kyle, played by Elise Robertson.
American Sniper is a 2014 American biographical war drama film directed and co-produced by Clint Eastwood and written and
executive-produced by Jason Hall, based on the memoir of the same name by Chris Kyle with Scott McEwen and Jim DeFelice.
The film follows the life of Kyle, who became the deadliest marksman in U.S.
military history with 255 kills from four tours in the Iraq War, 160 of
which were officially confirmed by the Department of Defense.
While Kyle was celebrated for his military successes, his tours of
duty took a heavy toll on his personal and family life.
It stars Bradley Cooper as Kyle and Sienna Miller as his wife Taya, with Luke Grimes, Jake McDorman,
Cory Hardrict, Kevin Lacz, Navid Negahban, and Keir O'Donnell in supporting roles.
American Sniper premiered at the American Film Institute Festival on November 11, 2014, and had a
limited theatrical release in the United States on December 25, 2014 by Warner Bros.
Pictures, followed by a wide release on January 16, 2015.
It received generally positive reviews, with praise for Cooper's lead performance and Eastwood's direction,
although it also attracted some controversy over its portrayal of both the Iraq War and Kyle himself.
The film grossed over $547 million worldwide, making it the 13th-highest-grossing film of 2014, the highest-grossing
film with a wide release during the month of January, and Eastwood's highest-grossing film to date.
At the 87th Academy Awards, American Sniper received six nominations, including Best Picture, Best
Adapted Screenplay, and Best Actor for Cooper, ultimately winning one for Best Sound Editing.
The film explores themes of sniper, based on novel or
book, affectation, grave, biography.
The tone is intense.